myitchytravelfeet.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy and Terms of Use

### Updated May 23, 3018

## Privacy Policy and Terms of Use

At My Itchy Travel Feet, we respect your privacy and are committed to securing and protecting the information that you share with us. This Privacy Policy describes what information we collect and how it is used and shared.

My Itchy Travel Feet found at https://myitchytravelfeet.com (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”). This statement only applies to this Website.

## What Information Do We Collect & How is it Used?

### Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website

We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address when you voluntarily submit information to the Website by subscribing to a newsletter.

### Automatically-Collected Information

We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked. The IP address may be linked with personally identifiable information. Unless otherwise noted in these Terms or as required by law, this information is not sold to or shared with third parties. The IP address may be used to block banned users from accessing the Website.

### Cookies

We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

###  **Security**

The Website relies on industry-standard security technologies and procedures to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, alteration, and/or destruction. The Website cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with the personal information it collects, and a breech may occur.

## How Your Information May Be Used

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

➡ To operate and maintain the Website;

➡ To create your account, identify you as a user of the Website, and customize the Website for your account;

➡ To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;

➡ To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;

➡ To respond to your inquiries;

➡ To provide you with user support;

➡ To track and measure advertising on the Website;

➡ To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

## Third-Party Use of Information

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

### Google Analytics

This service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

### Mail Chimp

This service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to Mail Chimp’s privacy policy for further information.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

## Anonymous Data

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

## Publicly Visible Information

Since the Website does not allow commenting on articles, your name, email address, avatar, profile description or website link is never publicly visible on our site.

## Cookies

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

## Advertising

### Display Ads

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

### Retargeting Ads

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

### Affiliate Program Participation

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

My Itchy Travel Feet is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

### Newsletters

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns.

Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

## Rights Related to Your Personal Information

### Opt-out

You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at donna@myitchytravelfeet.com to be removed from our mailing list.

### Access

You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to donna@myitchytravelfeet.com.

### Amend

You may contact us at donna@myitchytravelfeet.com to amend or update your personal information.

### Forget

In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to donna@myitchytravelfeet.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

## Sensitive Personal Information

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

## Children’s Information

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at donna@myitchytravelfeet.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## Terms of Use

### Product Reviews

The owner of the Website reviews travel related products. Some of these products are provided free in exchange for review, but with no promise of positive reviews.  The reader  will always be informed when the writer  has received a product for free. As a travel writer, the owner also accepts press trips. The owner will  tell you when a trip described on the website has been paid for by someone else. The site also features sponsored articles, which are clearly marked as such. The site includes affiliate ads within the copy of text, and they are clearly identifiable as ads.

### Contests

From time to time, the Website will host giveaways and contests. The Website is not responsible for the accuracy of the details of each freebie or fulfillment. The organization providing the item remains fully responsible for providing its description and handling fulfillment. Contest entrants agree to hold the Website harmless in the event that an organization does not fulfill its obligations.

### Links to Other Sites

My Itchy Travel Feet contains links to other websites, which are neither owned nor controlled by My Itchy Travel Feet. When users click on a link that takes them to another website, they have left My Itchy Travel Feet’s website. My Itchy Travel Feet is not responsible for the privacy policies of other sites. By providing links to other sites, My Itchy Travel Feet does not guarantee, approve, or endorse the information or products available at these sites.

###  **Jurisdiction**

The Website is based in Stevensville, Montana. As such, any information collected by My Itchy Travel Feet and/or voluntarily provided by My Itchy Travel Feet users will be subject to the laws and regulations of the United States. Should a dispute arise, My Itchy Travel Feet users agree that any civil action or legal proceeding shall be brought in the local, state, and federal courts of record located closest to Stevensville, Montana, or resolved under the rules of the American Arbitration Association (www.adr.org).

###  **Terms Updates**

The My Itchy Travel Feet Terms may be changed at any time and without notice. Should the Website undergo a change of ownership or make a substantial change regarding its use of personal information, My Itchy Travel Feet will notify individual subscribers using any subscription management services in place. Continued use of My Itchy Travel Feet’s subscription services and/or accessing its site indicates your acknowledgment of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

## Contact Information

At any time, please contact us at donna@myitchytravelfeet.com for questions related to this Privacy Policy or Terms of Use.
